<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/master/AnalysisInterventionEffects</url>
<date>2018-01-14</date>
<abstract>The <b>Intervention Effects</b> component helps you analyze data for the intervention effects.
<p>See <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=?" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow.</p></abstract>
<description>This component allows you to analyze data for the intervention effects.</description>

<inputs>
A tab-delimited or comma-separated text file: contains data to be analyzed.
</inputs>

<outputs>
<ul>
<li>A text file with data summary and linear modeling result</li>
<li>A pdf file with analysis result plots</li>
</ul>
</outputs>

<options>
<ul>
<li><b>Student Column:</b> choose the column with student ID.</li>
<li><b>Had Intervention Column:</b> choose the column that depicts if the student is in the intervention group. The allowed values are 0 and 1: 0 for control group and 1 for intervention group.</li>
<li><b>Pre Post Intervention Column:</b> choose the column that depicts if data in the row happened pre or post intervention. The allowed values are 0 and 1: 0 for pre-intervention and 1 for post-intervention.</li>  
<li><b>Number of Measurements:</b> how many measurements you want to analyze. Enter integer 1 to 5.</li>  
<li><b>Measurement N Column:</b> choose the column for measurement. Only numeric data is allowed in the column.</li>  
<li><b>Faceting Group for Measurement N:</b> choose "Had intervention" or "Pre and post intervention". "Had intervention" plots comparison of pre- and post-intervention with control and intervention condition as faceting groups. "Pre and post intervention" plots comparison of control and intervention condition with pre- and post-intervention as faceting groups.</li>  
</ul>

<p><b>Examples in the <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=?" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow</b></p>

<p><b>To analyze the effect of intervention on number of infractions and miscondtions:</b>
<ol>
<li>Student Column: choose "StudentRandomID" column.</li>
<li>Had Intervention Column: choose "hadIntervention" column.</li>
<li>Pre Post Intervention Column: choose "postIntervention" column.</li>
<li>Number of Measurements: enter 2.</li>
<li>Measurement 1 Column: choose "totalInfraction" column.</li>
<li>Faceting Group for Measurement 1: choose "Pre and post intervention".</li>
<li>Measurement 2 Column: choose "totalMisconduct" column.</li>
<li>Faceting Group for Measurement 2: choose "Pre and post intervention".</li>
</ol>
</p>

</options>

</info>
