<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/master/TransformRowMunging</url>
<date>2018-01-14</date>
<abstract>The <b>Row Munging</b> component provides various row operations for data manipulation. It allows you to keep rows, remove rows, and reset row values using column values.
<p>See <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2425" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow.</p></abstract>
<description>This component allows you to manipulate data at row level. It allows you to keep rows, remove rows, and reset row values using column values.</description>

<inputs>
A tab-delimited or comma-separated text file: contains data to be modified.
</inputs>

<outputs>
A tab-delimited file containing row munging result.
</outputs>

<options>
<ul>
<li><b>Row operation:</b> choose from remove rows, keep rows and reset row values.</li>
<li><b>Condition 1 Column:</b> define the column to compare.</li>
<li><b>Condition 1 Comparison Operator:</b> can be equal to, greater than (for numeric data), greater than or equal to (for numeric data), less than (for numeric data), less than or equal to (for numeric data), or contain (doesn't work when the compared-to value is a column).</li>  
<li><b>Condition 1 Compare to Value Type:</b> define the value type for the compared-to variable of the first comparison condition. It can be NA, constants, or value from another column.</li>  
<li><b>Condition 1 Compare to Value:</b> when Condition 1 Compare to Value Type is defined to be constants, this field shows. Multiple values are allowed but should be separated by comma. Comparison is case insensitive. </li>  
<li><b>Condition 1 Compare to Column:</b> when Condition 1 Compare to Value Type is defined to be value from column, this field shows. Operator contain doesn't work for this situation.</li>  
<li><b>Add Condition 2:</b> choose Yes when you want to add a second condition to the row choosing rule.</li>
<li><b>Logical Operator for Condition 1 and 2:</b> choose a logical operator, and or or, to use between condition 1 and condition 2.</li>
<li><b>Condition 2 Column:</b> define a second column to compare</li>
<li><b>Condition 2 Comparison Operator:</b> can be equal to, greater than (for numeric data), greater than or equal to (for numeric data), less than (for numeric data), less than or equal to (for numeric data), or contain (doesn't work when the compared-to value is a column).</li>  
<li><b>Condition 2 Compare to Value Type:</b> define the value type for the compared-to variable of the second comparison condition. It can be NA, constants, or value from another column.</li>
<li><b>Condition 2 Compare to Value:</b> when Condition 2 Compare to Value Type is defined to be constants, this field shows. Multiple values are allowed but should be separated by comma. Comparison is case insensitive. </li>  
<li><b>Condition 2 Compare to Column:</b> when Condition 2 Compare to Value Type is defined to be value from column, this field shows. Operator contain doesn't work for this situation.</li>  
<li><b>Add Condition 3:</b> choose Yes when you want to add a third condition to the row choosing rule.</li>
<li><b>Logical Operator for Condition 2 and 3:</b> choose a logical operator, and or or, to use between condition 2 and condition 3.</li>
<li><b>Condition 3 Column:</b> define a third column to compare</li>
<li><b>Condition 3 Comparison Operator:</b> can be equal to, greater than (for numeric data), greater than or equal to (for numeric data), less than (for numeric data), less than or equal to (for numeric data), or contain (doesn't work when the compared-to value is a column).</li>  
<li><b>Condition 3 Compare to Value Type:</b> define the value type for the compared-to variable of the third comparison condition. It can be NA, constants, or value from another column.</li>
<li><b>Condition 3 Compare to Value:</b> when Condition 3 Compare to Value Type is defined to be constants, this field shows. Multiple values are allowed but should be separated by comma. Comparison is case insensitive. </li>  
<li><b>Condition 3 Compare to Column:</b> when Condition 3 Compare to Value Type is defined to be value from column, this field shows. Operator contain doesn't work for this situation.</li>  
</ul>


<p><b>Examples in the <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2425" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow</b></p>

<p>Choose rows that contains "number_of_attempt" or "number_of_lecture" in column "Feature Name":
<ol>
<li>Row Operation: choose "Keep rows"</li>
<li>Condition 1 Column: choose "Feature Name"</li>
<li>Condition 1 Comparison Operator: choose "Contain".</li>
<li>Condition 1 Compare to Value Type: choose "Constants".</li>
<li>Condition 1 Compare to Value: enter "number_of_attempt, number_of_lecture".</li>
<li>Add Condition 2: choose "No"</li>
</ol>
</p>
<p>Choose rows that contains "number_of_attempt" or "number_of_lecture" in column "Feature Name", and only keep "Longitudinal Feature Week" after the fourth week:
<ol>
<li>Row Operation: choose "Keep rows"</li>
<li>Condition 1 Column: choose "Feature Name"</li>
<li>Condition 1 Comparison Operator: choose "Contain".</li>
<li>Condition 1 Compare to Value Type: choose "Constants".</li>
<li>Condition 1 Compare to Value: enter "number_of_attempt, number_of_lecture".</li>
<li>Add Condition 2: choose "Yes"</li>
<li>Logical Operator for Condition 1 and 2: choose "And".</li>
<li>Condition 2 Column: choose "Longitudinal Feature Week"</li>
<li>Condition 2 Comparison Operator: choose "Greater than".</li>
<li>Condition 1 Compare to Value Type: choose "Constants".</li>
<li>Condition 1 Compare to Value: enter "4".</li>
<li>Add Condition 3: choose "No"</li>
</ol>
</p>

</options>

</info>
