<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/dev/TutorTranscriptEvaluation</url>
<date>2024-09-20</date>
<abstract>The <b>Tutor Transcript Evaluation</b> component gives users the OpenAI's evaluation to the transcript of tutoring session. We are using OpenAI gpt-3.5-turb-instruct engine.
<p>See <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=4333" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow.</p></abstract>
<description>This component gives users the OpenAI's evaluation to the transcript of tutoring session.
</description>

<inputs>
<ul>
<li>Transcript of tutoring session. Transcript can be in VTT, CSV or text format. Zipped multiple transcripts can be used. <b>Required</b></li>
<li>GPT prompt in plain text format. This text string must be included in the prompt file: "Transcript Start --- --- Transcript End." <b>Not Required</b>. Sample prompts: <a href="https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/blob/dev/TutorTranscriptEvaluation/test/test_data/math_error_filter_prompt.txt" target="_blank">filter prompt at session level</a>, <a href="https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/blob/dev/TutorTranscriptEvaluation/test/test_data/math_error_evaluation_prompt.txt" target="_blank">evaluation at session level</a>, <a href="https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/blob/dev/TutorTranscriptEvaluation/test/test_data/math_error_by_line_prompt_gpt35.txt" target="_blank">evaluation by line</a></li>
</ul>
</inputs>

<outputs>
<ul>
<li>The CSV file that has OpenAI's responses. </li>
</ul>
</outputs>

<options>
<ul>
<li><strong>OpenAI API Key:</strong> Obtain your API key from OpenAI's website.</li>
<li><strong>Transcript File Type:</strong> Select from the following options: Zip of VTT Files, Zip of CSV Files, Zip of TXT Files, Single VTT, Single CSV, or Single TXT.</li>
<li><strong>CSV Utterance Column:</strong> Visible only when the file type is Zip of CSV Files or Single CSV. Use this to specify which column contains the session's utterances.</li>
<li><strong>Number of Trials:</strong> Number of times GPT will be queried with the same transcript.</li>
<li><strong>Max Tokens:</strong> Maximum number of tokens allowed in GPT's response.</li>
<li><strong>GPT Temperature:</strong> A value between 0 and 1; lower values make the output more focused and deterministic.</li>
<li><strong>Compose Prompt Now:</strong> When checked, you are required to enter your own prompt in the Prompt field. If left unchecked, prompt must be imported as a file, see the Inputs section above.</li>
<li><strong>Prompt:</strong> Only available if the checkbox of Compose Prompt Now is checked. The text "Transcript Start --- --- Transcript End." is required to be included in the field. Non ACSII characters are not allowed in this field, so you must clean them up before the component can run. </li>
</ul>

</options>


</info>
