<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
    <author>Philip Pavlik
        <email>ppavlik@memphis.edu</email>
    </author>
    <url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/memphis/AnalysisTkt</url>
    <date>2018-03-28</date>
    <abstract>The <b>Temporal Knowledge Tracing</b> (TKT) model is logistic regression predicting Outcome column correctness.</abstract>
    <details>TKT combines aspects of Performance Factors Analysis (PFA) available in LearnSphere and the ACT-R model of human cognition. Email the author directly with bug reports for this component.</details>

    <inputs>
        <b>Transaction export with TKT features (from Generate TKT Features Transform component)</b>
    </inputs>

    <outputs>
        <b>Transaction export with model predictions attached, R model output with parameter values, R model fit statistics in xml,</b>
    </outputs>

    <options>
        <p>  
            <b>Type</b> - the user can select to find the best fitting model, or 5 times 2-fold cross-validation. 5 times 2-fold crossvalidation works only at the subject level (subject stratified) under the assumption that generalization to other subjects is what is desired. The user has the option to randomly create folds or to use the folds existing in a prior run of this component (i.e. if you feed the transaction file back into the analysis, you can choose read to use the exact same folds for a replication).</p>
        <p>
            <b>Use categorical intercepts</b> - allows either a single fixed effect intercept for the model, or fixed effect intercepts for any single categorical variable. This allows the user to estimate prior knowledge based on a KC model. This mechanism is very flexible and can be used for other categorical variables, such as the student identifier or the content unit (e.g. pretest, practice, posttest).</p>
        <p>
            <b>Optimized parameters</b> - The LearnSphere implementation is highly configurable, allowing 4 performance tracing features and 3 memory tracing features to be used for prediction of learner performance. The user can compute the model using any combination of these 7 factors, each of which can be either use fixed parameters or optimally fitted. </p>
        <p>In order the 10 options (set to 1 to optimize, 0 to use fixed) of the model refer to:</p>
        <ol>
                <li>successes of subordinate KC - failures of subordinate KC</li>
                <li>successes of superordinate KC - failures for superordinate KC</li>
                <li>successes of same response term - failures of same response term depends on CF (Correct Answer) in data</li>
                <li>successes of all subject KCs - failures of all subject KCs</li>
                <li>interactive function of decay from first superordinate trial, log of the count of prior subordinate repetitions, and mean spacing</li>
                <li>interactive function of decay from first superordinate trial and log of the count of prior superordinate repetitions</li>
                <li>interactive function of decay from first superordinate trial and log of the count of prior response repetitions</li>
                <li>decay parameter switch used for 5,6 and 7 (set to 0 to use fixed parameter 8)</li>
                <li>spacing parameter switch used for 5 (set to 0 to use fixed parameters 9 and 11)</li>
                <li>interference parameter see Pavlik and Anderson (2005) switch used for 5,6 and 7 (set to 0 to use fixed parameter 10)</li>
        </ol>
        <p>
            <b>Fixed parameters</b> - In the event that a parameter is turned off (set to 0 in optimized list), then the fixed value listed here will be used. The default fixed values turn each component off.  (Note that a default of 1 turns interference (10th parameter) off. Similarly, the default of 1 is also needed for the 11th fixed parameter, which is also for spacing effects)</p>
    
        <p>
            <b>Categorical intercept column</b> - If the user requests categorical intercepts, the column designating the categories to be fit with an additional intercept is designated here.</p>
    </options>

</info>
