<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/master/TransformPivot</url>
<date>2018-01-14</date>
<abstract>The <b>Pivot</b> component mimics the Excel pivot function to allow users to aggregate and transform data.
<p>See <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2348" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow.</p></abstract>
<description>This component allows you to aggregate and transform data. The functionality that it provides is very similiar to the one used in Excel.</description>

<inputs><ul>
<li>tab-delimited file: contains data to be modified.</li>
</ul></inputs>

<outputs>
Tab-delimited file contains pivoted result.
</outputs>

<options>
 <ul>
<li>Aggregation Method: functions to be used in aggregation, e.g., count, sum, min, max, sd and median</li>
<li>Measurement: the original columns that would be used for measurement of pivoting. Multiple selection is allowed.</li>
<li>Define Rows: yes or no. Selecting yes will make option "Rows in Pivot Table" appear. </li>
<li>Rows in Pivot Table: rows that would appear as rows in the pivot result table. Multiple selection is allowed.</li>
<li>Define Columns: yes or no. Selecting yes will make option "Columns in Pivot Table" appear. </li>
<li>Columns in Pivot Table: the columns to be included in the pivot result table. This provides more specific measurement for the subgroups of the chosen columns. Multiple selection is allowed.</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Examples in the <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2348" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow</b></p>

<p><b>For the average time spent on step for the entire dataset:</b>
<ol>
<li>Choose mean for Aggregation Method</li>  
<li>Choose Step Duration (sec) for Measurement</li>
<li>Choose No for Define Rows</li>
<li>Choose No for Define Columns</li>
</ol>
</p>
<p><b>For the average time spent on step per student:</b>
<ol>
<li>Choose mean for Aggregation Method</li>  
<li>Choose Step Duration (sec) for Measurement</li>
<li>Choose Yes for Define Rows</li>
<li>Choose Anon Student Id for Rows in Pivot Table</li>  
<li>Choose No for Define Columns</li>
</ol>
</p>

<p><b>For the average time spent on step for each problem per student:</b>
<ol>
<li>Choose mean for Aggregation Method</li>  
<li>Choose Step Duration (sec) for Measurement</li>
<li>Choose Yes for Define Rows</li>
<li>Choose Anon Student Id for Rows in Pivot Table</li>  
<li>Choose Yes for Define Columns</li>
<li>Choose Problem Name for Columns in Pivot Table</li>
</ol>
</p>

<p><b>For the average time spent on step for each problem and each problem view per student:</b>
<ol>
<li>Choose sum for Aggregation Method</li>  
<li>Choose Step Duration (sec) for Measurement</li>
<li>Choose Yes for Define Rows</li>
<li>Choose Anon Student Id for Rows in Pivot Table</li>  
<li>Choose Yes for Define Columns</li>
<li>Choose Problem Name and Problem View (by holding down ctrl key on Windows or cmd key on Mac) for Columns in Pivot Table</li>
</ol>
</p>


</options>

</info>
