<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/dev/OLIResourceUseDataGenerator</url>
<date>2017-03-10</date>
<abstract>The <b>OLI Resource Use</b> aggregates OLI log transaction data into resource usage data such as action count, action time, 
page view count, page view time and etc. It requires two input file: transaction file and user session map file. The only acceptable column headers for the transaction import file are in the following order: guid, sess_ref, source, time, timezone, action, external_object_id, container, concept_this, concept_req, eastern_time, server_receipt_time, info_type, info. The user session map matches student ID to user session ID which appears in the transacton file. The only acceptable column headers for user session map are in the following order: user_sess, user_id. The output file contains the following headers: student, action count, action time, page view count, page view time, action to page view count, action to page view time, page view to action count, page view to action time, media play count, media play time, media play to view page count, media play to view page time, action to media play count, and action to media play time.</abstract>
<description>This component helps aggregate OLI transaction data into resource usage data. It requires two input file: transaction file and user session map file. The only acceptable column headers for the transaction import file are in the following order: guid, sess_ref, source, time, timezone, action, external_object_id, container, concept_this, concept_req, eastern_time, server_receipt_time, info_type, info. The user session map matches student ID to user session ID which appears in the transacton file. The only acceptable column headers for user session map are in the following order: user_sess, user_id. The output file contains the following headers: student, action count, action time, page view count, page view time, action to page view count, action to page view time, page view to action count, page view to action time, media play count, media play time, media play to view page count, media play to view page time, action to media play count, and action to media play time.</description>

<inputs>
<b><ul><li>OLI transaction data file</li>
<li>OLI user session map</li></ul></b>
</inputs>

<outputs>
<b>The tab-delimited file for resource usage.</b>
</outputs>

<options>
</options>

</info>
