<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>

<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/master/TransformDeidentify</url>
<date>2017-03-10</date>
<abstract>The <b>Deidentify</b> component helps de-identify student ID in a data file. It takes two input files: a file that contains the actual student ID that are to be de-identified and a file that contains the mapping for the actual student ID and the anonymous student ID.
 If an actual student ID can not be found in the map file, the component will first try to reconcile the actual ID to the Datashop anonymous student ID. If the actual student ID can't be found in 
Datashop database, a new anonymous student ID will be generated by the component. Any new user anonymous ID will be included in the new output user map file.</abstract>
<description>This component helps de-identify student ID in a file. It takes two input files: a file that contains the actual student ID that are to be de-identified and a file that contains the mapping for the actual student ID and the anonymous student ID.
 If an actual student ID can not be found in the map file, the component will first try to reconcile the actual ID to the Datashop anonymous student ID. If the actual student ID can't be found in 
Datashop database, a new anonymous student ID will be generated by the component. Any new user anonymous ID will be included in the new output user map file.</description>

<inputs>
<b><ul><li>A tab-delimited file</li>
<li>A user map file</li></ul></b>
</inputs>

<outputs>
<b><ul><li>The data file with student ID de-identified</li>
<li>New user map file including existing and new user ID mappings</li></ul></b>
</outputs>

<options>
<ul>
<li>User Map Actual User ID Column Name: the column name for the actual user ID in the map file</li>
<li>User Map Anonymous User ID Column Name: the column name for the anonymous user ID in the map file</li>
<li>File Actual User ID Column Name: the column name for the actual user ID in the data file</li>
<li>Case Sensitive: False/True, default is False</li>
<li>Delimiter Pattern: default is tab (\t)</li></ul>
</options>

</info>
