<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>, MIT
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/dev/AnalysisFastAfmAndCv</url>
<date>2018-01-14</date>
<abstract>The <b>Fast AFM and CV</b> component uses Python Logistic Regression function to generate results for AFM and Cross Validation in a relatively fast speed.
<p>See <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2349" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow.</p></abstract>
<description>This component uses Python Logistic Regression function to generate results for AFM and Cross Validation in a relatively fast speed.</description>

<inputs>
<p>A tab-delimited file. Although ideally this component uses the Datashop Student-step export file, it can also run with the following minimum columns (column headers have to match exactly, see <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2349" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow for details):</p>
<ol>
<li>Anon Student Id</li>
<li>Problem Hierarchy, can be empty as long as either Problem Name or Step Name has value</li>
<li>Problem Name, can be empty as long as either Problem Hierarchy or Step Name has value</li>
<li>Step Name, can be empty as long as either Problem Hierarchy or Problem Name has value</li>
<li>First Transaction Time, can't be empty</li>
<li>First Attempt, acceptable values are correct/incorrect/hint</li>
<li>KC (A Model)</li>
</ol>
<p>Other requirement for the input file: data needs to be ordered by Anon Student Id and then by First Transaction Time</p>

</inputs>

<outputs>
<ul>
<li>A analysis-summary.txt, mimicing Datashop model values export report </li>
<li>A student-step file with the predicted error rate of the selected KC model replaced by the newly computed prediction</li>
<li>An XML file with the coefficients of the logistic regression model</li>
<li>An XML file with the skills' and students' parameters computed by the logistic regression model</li>
</ul>
</outputs>

<options>
 <ul>
<li>KC model</li>
<li>Compute cross validation: yes or no, whether to compute cross validation RMSE</li>
<li>What type of cross valication: item blocked, student blocked or both, default is both</li>
<li>Cross validation fold: maxium allowed is 10, default is 3</li>
</ul>
</options>

</info>
