<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>Nirmal Patel
  <email>nirmal@playpowerlabs.com</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/dev/CurriculumPacing</url>
<date>March 14, 2019</date>
<abstract>The <b>Curriculum Pacing</b> component allows users to visualize and explore end-to-end curriculum data. To see what Curriculum Pacing is and what does it look like, please refer to <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-91464-0_38">this paper</a>. To get more insight into the parameters of the component, please refer to <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/331346120_Using_Curriculum_Pacing_in_LearnSphere_to_Visualize_Student_Learning_Trajectories">this paper</a>. In a nutshell, using this component, you will be able to see how students progress through the curriculum or problem hierarchy over time.</abstract>
<description>Curriculum Pacing is a way to visualize student learning trajectories through curriculum units and sections. This visualization is suitable to quickly explore end-to-end curriculum data and see patterns of student learning. Try creating this visualization for different sub-samples of the data having different properties and it might reveal differences in student learning paths in the different cohorts.</description>

<inputs><ul>
<li>Input 1 - <b>student-problem</b>: This input is either data in the DataShop student-problem format or any TSV dataset with these columns: Anon Student Id (String), Problem Hierarchy (String), Problem Start Time (ISO Timestamp), Corrects (Number), Incorrects (Number)</li>
<li>Input 2 (optional) - <b>hierarchy-order</b>: This optional input is a CSV file that gives the correct linear order of the values in the Problem Hierarchy column. This is a two column CSV file with these two column names: Problem Hierarchy (String), Problem Hierarchy Order (Number) </li></ul>
</inputs>

<outputs>
<b>PDF</b>
</outputs>

<options>
<ul>
<li>PlotType - (1) Usage - Just show student usage over time (2) Usage and performance - Show both student usage and performance over time</li>
<li>TimeScaleType -- Relative or Absolute</li>
<li>TimeScaleRes -- Day, Week, or Month</li>
<li>RelMinTimeUnit -- Integer, applies only to relative time scale. Used to filter the X axis of the plot. Sets the minimum time unit. For example, if time scale is relative, and time scale resolution is week, min time unit = 5 will start all students at their 5th week of usage.</li>
<li>RelMaxTimeUnit -- Integer, similar to RelMinTimeUnit, sets maximum X axis limit.</li>
<li>AbsMinTimeUnit -- ISO Timestamp, applies only to absolute time scale. Used to filter X axis of the plot. Sets the minimum time.</li>
<li>AbsMaxTimeUnit -- ISO Timestamp, similar to AbsMaxTimeUnit, sets maximum X axis limit.</li>
</ul>
</options>

</info>
