<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/master/OliDemographic</url>
<date>2022-06-14</date>
<abstract><p>The <b>OliDemographic</b> component can transform problem and transaction data into a Datashop formatted csv file with student performance on oli courses.</p>
<p>The required input fields are a string that is the problem name of demographic survey questions and a string that is the problem name of confidence survey questions.
</p>
<p>There is one type of output: a csv file called Demographic_and_Confidence_Survey. This csv file contains student answers for every demographic and confidence survey
  question in the oli course that the input files represent. These are organized every row by student id and every column by question id. The csv file also contains
  student response time to the confidence survey.
  To get the problem content for the column headers of the output: go to the dataset in Datashop and click on Problem List. The problem content will
  be available for the problems that are underlined. Click on these to view the problem content. The only datasets that will have problem content available
  will be the ones with a "lego icon" next to transactions when on the "My Datasets" page.
 <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/help?page=export#table-by-student-step" target="_blank">Datashop help</a>
</p>
</abstract>
<description>This component allows you to transform student problem data and transaction data into a Datashop formatted csv file.</description>

<inputs>
Tab-delimited problem file and transaction file. See Abstract section for required fields.
</inputs>

<outputs>
Tab-delimited csv file containing student performance data on demographic and confidence survey questions.
</outputs>

<options>
 <ul>
<li>Problem Name of demographic survey questions.</li>
<li>Problem Name of confidence survey questions.</li>
</ul>
</options>

</info>
