<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/master/DeidentifyDialogue</url>
<date>2024-09-20</date>
<abstract>The <b>Deidentify Dialogue</b> component gives users option between Azure langauge services (paid), Amazon Comprehend(paid), or Presidio (free) for PII
 detection. Also, when it comes to replacing the PII, users have the option to either encode with hash values or use HIPS..
<p>See <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=3919" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow.</p></abstract>
<description>This component gives users option between Azure langauge services (paid), Amazon Comprehend (paid), or Presidio (free) for PII
detection.</description>

<inputs>
<ul>
<li>A CSV file or any text file that has PII that needs to be deidentified. <b>Required</b></li>
<li>A CSV file that can be used for encoding the PII. It should include a column for the PII values and a column for the hash values. <b>Optional</b>, only visible when the Encoding option is set to Yes (see the Options section of this document)</li>
</ul>
</inputs>

<outputs>
<ul>
<li>The CSV file or the text file that has PII deidentified. </li>
<li>A CSV file with PII names and the hash values used. If an encoding file is used, this CSV has the updated encoding hash values.</li>
</ul>
</outputs>

<options>
 <ul>
<li>Anonymize Method: choose from Presidio, Azure or Comprehend. Presidio is free.</li>
<li>Detection Threshold: the scoring threshold for Presidio, .</li>
<li>HIPS: hidden in plain sight. If no, the Use Encoding File option is visible.</li>
<li>File Type: choose from CSV or Non-CSV</li>
<li>Skip Columns: choose Yes if you have columns to skip the deidentification process. This option is only present when CSV is selected for File type option.</li>
<li>Columns to Skip: select columns to skip the deidentification process. This option is only present when Yes is selected for the Skip Columns option.</li>
<li>Use Encoding File: choose yes to provide encoding file for hash values. This option is only present when No is selected for HIPS</li>
<li>Name Column in Encoding File: choose the column that has PII names in the encoding file. This option is only present when Yes is selected for the Use Encoding File option.</li>
<li>Hash Column in Encoding File: choose the column that has hash values in the encoding file. This option is only present when Yes is selected for the Use Encoding File option.</li>
<li>API Key: only present when Azure is selected. <b>API key can be viewed when you shared your WF with others.</b></li>
<li>END POINT: only present when Azure is selected. <b>END POINT can be viewed when you shared your WF with others.</b></li>
<li>AWS Access Key: only present when Comprehend is selected. <b>Your AWS Secret Key can be viewed when you shared your Workflow with others.</b></li>
<li>AWS Secret Key: only present when Comprehend is selected. <b>Your AWS Access Key can be viewed when you shared your Workflow with others.</b></li>

</ul>

<p>
The <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=3919" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow shows two ways to use the Deidentidy Dialogue component:
<ul>
<li>Use Presidio to deidentify a tutoring transcript using HIPS</li>
<li>Use Presidio to deidentify a CSV file with provided encoding hash values</li>
</ul>
</p>
</options>


</info>
