<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/dev/FuzzyMatching</url>
<date>2022-10-19</date>
<abstract><p>The <b>Fuzzy Match</b> component uses Levenshtein Distance Ratio to determine the similarity between two character sequences. It suggests if there is a match based on the difference between Levenshtein Distance Ratio and the threshold that the user specified.</p>
<p>The component offers two matching modes:
<ol>
<li>File to File: fuzzy-match columns from two separate files</li>
<li>File to String: fuzzy-match a column of a file to a string</li>
</ol></p>
<p>See <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2771" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow.</p>
</abstract>
<description>This component uses Levenshtein Distance Ratio to determine the similarity between two character sequences. It suggests if there is a match based on the difference between Levenshtein Distance Ratio and the threshold that the user specified.
The component accepts two matching modes: File to File and File to String.</description>

<inputs>
<p>For File to File mode: Two text files (CSV or tab-delimited) are required.</p>
<p>For File to String mode: One text file (CSV or tab-delimited) is required.</p>
</inputs>

<outputs>
Tab-delimited file containing matching result
</outputs>

<options>
<p>For File to File mode:
<ol>
<li>Threshold: an integer between 40 and 95.</li>
<li>Number of Columns to Match: integer 1 to 4.</li>
<li>File 1 Column X (1-4) to Match: pick a column from the first input file for matching</li>
<li>File 2 Column X (1-4) to Match: pick a column from the second input file for matching</li>
</ol>
</p>
<p>For File to String mode:
<ol>
<li>Threshold: an integer between 40 and 95.</li>
<li>Column to Match: pick a column from the input file for matching</li>
<li>String to Match: non-empty string for matching</li>
</ol>
</p>
<p>See <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2771" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow for a File to File match and a File to String match. </p>

</options>


</info>
