<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/master/AnalysisRglm</url>
<date>2017-09-14</date>
<abstract>
<p>The <b>Linear Modeling</b> component allows users to conduct R 
    <a href="https://www.rdocumentation.org/packages/stats/versions/3.4.1/topics/lm">lm</a>, 
    <a href="https://www.rdocumentation.org/packages/lme4/versions/1.1-13/topics/lmer">lmer</a>, 
    <a href="https://www.rdocumentation.org/packages/stats/versions/3.4.1/topics/glm">glm</a> and 
    <a href="https://www.rdocumentation.org/packages/lme4/versions/1.1-13/topics/glmer">glmer</a> functions on a data file of their choice.</p>
<p>For glm and glmer, the variance and link families provided include: binomial (link = logit), binomial (link = probit), binomial (link = cloglog), gaussian (link = identity), Gamma (link = inverse), Gamma (link = identity), Gamma (link = log), inverse.gaussian (link = 1/mu^2), poisson (link = log), poisson (link = identity), poisson (link = sqrt).</p>
<p>Users can choose a column for response. For binomial families, the component will convert true/false and correct/incorrect/hint values to 1 or 0. For other families, the component only allows numeric values for response column.</p>
<p>The component provides convenient ways to users to construct formula for analysis. For lm/glm option, users can choose columns for fixed factor(s). For lmer/glmer, in addition to fixed factor(s), users can choose columns for random factor(s) with or without intercept, and with or without categorical nesting factor.
</p>
<p>The back-end of the component runs on R.</p>
<p>To make glmer/lmer runs fast and efficiently, we apply glmerControl with nloptwrap as optimizer and lmerControl with optimx as optimizer.</p>
<p>To make glm/lm runs fast and efficiently, we use speedglm and speedlm respectively.</p>
<p>See <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2347" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow.</p>
</abstract>
<description></description>

<inputs>
<ul><li>A tab-delimited data file.</li></ul>
</inputs>

<outputs><ul>
<li>A text file containing R analysis summary.</li>
</ul></outputs>

<options>
<ul>
<li>Modeling type: lm, lmer, glm or glmer.</li>
<li>Family: available only for glm or glmer.</li>
<li>Response: for binomial families, the component will convert true/false and correct/incorrect/hint values to 1 or 0. For other families, the component only allows numeric values for response column.</li>
<li>Fixed effects: can choose one or more factors at a time. Use the arrow buttons to edit the final fixed effects. If interaction type "*" is selected, all possible fixed factors will be added to the final list, thus the final formula. For example, KC*KC-opportunity results in three items KC, KC-opportunity and KC:KC-opportunity to be added to the final formula.</li>
<li>Random effects: grouping/random factor is required while nesting and independent/fixed factors are optional. For examples: choosing "student" as grouping/random factor alone results in (1+student) added to the final list; choosing "student" as grouping/random factor, "class" as nesting factor and "KC-opportunity" as independent/fixed factor results in (KC-opportunity|class/student) added to the final list. If "no" intercept is selected, (0+KC-opportunity|class/student) is added.</li>
<li>Formula: uneditable field. Content is constructed by what are selected in fixed effect and random effect fields.</li>
<li>Prediction Column Name: default is Predicted Error Rate (Linear Model)</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Examples: (see <a href="https://pslcdatashop.web.cmu.edu/LearnSphere?workflowId=2347" target="_blank">demo</a> workflow)</b></p>

<p><b>Formula used for iAFM: First Attempt ~ Opportunity (A Model) + Opportunity (A Model)|Anon Student Id + Opportunity (A Model)|KC (A Model)</b>
<ol>
<li><b>First Attempt:</b> Choose First Attempt for Response</li>  
<li><b>Opportunity (A Model):</b> In Fixed Effects, choose Opportunity (A Model) for Fixed factor</li>  
<li><b>Opportunity (A Model)|Anon Student Id:</b> In Random Effects, choose Anon Student Id for Grouping/Random factor, and choose Opportunity (A Model) for Independent/Fixed factor</li>
<li><b>Opportunity (A Model)|KC (A Model):</b> In Random Effects, choose KC (A Model) for Grouping/Random factor, and choose Opportunity (A Model) for Independent/Fixed factor</li>
<li><b>Prediction Column Name:</b> Predicted Error Rate (A Model)</li>
</ol>
</p>

<p><b>Formula used for strong AFM: First Attempt ~ 1|Anon Student Id + KC (A Model) + KC (A Model):Opportunity (A Model)</b>
<ol>
<li><b>First Attempt:</b> Choose First Attempt for Response</li>  
<li><b>1|Anon Student Id:</b> In Random Effects, choose Anon Student Id for Grouping/Random factor</li>
<li><b>KC (A Model):</b> In Fixed Effects, choose KC (A Model) for Fixed factor</li>  
<li><b>KC (A Model):Opportunity (A Model):</b> In Fixed Effects, choose KC (A Model) and Opportunity (A Model) for Fixed factor, and choose ":" for interaction</li>  
<li><b>Prediction Column Name:</b> Predicted Error Rate (A Model)</li>
</ol>
</p>

<p><b>Formula used for Hierarchical AFM: First Attempt ~ 1|Anon Student Id + 1|KC (A Model)/KC (Item Model) + KC (A Model):Opportunity (A Model)</b>
<ol>
<li><b>First Attempt:</b> Choose First Attempt for Response</li>  
<li><b>1|Anon Student Id:</b> In Random Effects, choose Anon Student Id for Grouping/Random factor</li>
<li><b>1|KC (A Model)/KC (Item Model):</b> In Random Effects, choose KC (Item Model) for Grouping/Random factor, and choose KC (A Model) for Nesting factor</li>
<li><b>KC (A Model):Opportunity (A Model):</b> In Fixed Effects, choose KC (A Model) and Opprotunity (A Model) for Fixed factor; and choose ":" for interaction</li>  
<li><b>Prediction Column Name:</b> Predicted Error Rate (A Model)</li>
</ol>
</p>

</options>

</info>
