<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>Philip Pavlik
  <email>ppavlik@memphis.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/master/LKT</url>
<date>March 01, 2021</date>
<abstract>The <b>LKT</b> component is implements logisitc knowledge tracing.</abstract>
<details>
        This <b>LKT</b> component fits models usign the LKT package in R https://github.com/Optimal-Learning-Lab/LKT. Below are examples of how to fill in the boxes for models with various numbers of terms.

        For each term, there can be a feature, a component the feature applies to, a list of fixed parameters (assuming the feature needs these), and a list of seed paramters (used if fixed parameters needed but not provided). These feature are documented in this paper https://arxiv.org/abs/2005.00869 and in the R package above.

        The $ operator computes coefficients for each level of the KC for the feature. The @ operator computes the feature as a random effect, and may only be used for random intercepts. Note: single-KC models should not be attempted, but using LKT, a feature that is computed per Anon Student Id level is equivalent to a single-KC model.

    Examples:

    <p>To produce modified AFM with fixed-effect intercept for KC, propdec used to trace overall student learning, and only a single slope for learning. :
      <ol>
              <li>Term 1: propdec; Anon Student Id; .9</li>
              <li>Term 2: intercept; KC (Default)</li>
              <li>Term 3: lineafm; KC (Default)</li></ol>
    </p>

  <p>To produce standard AFM with random-effect intercepts for student and KC and per KC lineafm learning (linear effect of opportunities):
      <ol>
              <li>Term 1: intercept@; Anon Student Id</li>
              <li>Term 2: intercept@; KC (Default)</li>
              <li>Term 3: lineafm$; KC (Default)</li></ol>
</p>

<p>To produce intercepts and some feature fits to clusters (ones that don't rely on timing factors). In the example, term 2 finds a coefficient for the log of prior success in cluster 1 only. :
  <ol>
          <li>Term 1: intercept; Clusters</li>
          <li>Term 2: logsuc; KC (Default)%Clusters%1</li></ol>

</p>
      <p>To produce standard PFA with random-effect intercepts for student and KC:
        <ol>
                <li>Term 1: intercept@; Anon Student Id</li>
    <li>Term 2: intercept@; KC (Default)</li>
    <li>Term 3: linesuc$; KC (Default)</li>
    <li>Term 4: linefail$; KC (Default)</li></ol>
</p>
      <p>To produce AFM with fixed-effect intercepts for student and KC and long-term forgetting:
        <ol>
                <li>Term 1: intercept; Anon Student Id</li>
    <li>Term 2: intercept; KC (Default)</li>
    <li>Term 3: base2$; KC (Default);  .3,.05</li></ol>
</p>
      <p>To produce AFM model with fixed-effect intercepts for student and KC, KC long-term forgetting, and item level PFA (simple hierarcical domain model)
        <ol>
                <li>Term 1: intercept; Anon Student Id</li>
    <li>Term 2: intercept; KC (Default)</li>
    <li>Term 3: base2$; KC (Default); .3,.05</li>
    <li>Term 4: linesuc$; KC (Item)</li>
    <li>Term 5: linefail$; KC (Item)</li></ol>
</p>
      <p>To produce PFA with student ability tracing :
        <ol>
                <li>Term 1: propdec; Anon Student Id; .9</li>
    <li>Term 2: intercept; KC (Default)</li>
    <li>Term 3: linesuc$; KC (Default)</li>
    <li>Term 4: linefail$; KC (Default)</li></ol>
</p>
      <p>To produce PFA with long-term forgetting and random-effect intercepts for student and KC:
        <ol>
                <li>Term 1: intercept@; Anon Student Id</li>
    <li>Term 2: intercept@; KC (Default)</li>
    <li>Term 3: base2suc$; KC (Default); .3,.05</li>
    <li>Term 4: base2fail$; KC (Default); .3,.05</li></ol>
</p>
</details>

<inputs>
    <b>Transaction export with LKT features (for some models).</b>
</inputs>

<outputs>
    <b>Transaction export with model predictions attached, R model output with parameter values, R model fit statistics in xml</b>
</outputs>

<options>
      <p><b>Modle Name</b> - passed to subsequent components for graphing.</p>
      <p><b>Model Terms</b> - The user can specify up to 10 terms. See details.</p>
      <p><b>Global intercept</b> - Some models may want a single fixed intercept to be fit.</p>
      <p><b>Elstictest</b> - Not working, Leave FALSE.</p>
      <p><b>Latency Model</b> - Report?</p>
      <p><b>Verbose</b> - Report more sometimes?</p>
      <p><b>Fixed NLPs</b> - Do any of the terms require a fixed non-linear parameter?</p>
      <p><b>Seed NLPs</b> - Do any of the terms require a search seed non-linear parameter?</p>
      <p><b>Fixed coefficients</b> - Do any of the terms use a fixed regression coefficient that is not optimizied.</p>


</options>

</info>
