<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<info>
<author>DataShop@CMU
  <email>datashop-help@lists.andrew.cmu.edu</email>
</author>
<url>https://github.com/LearnSphere/WorkflowComponents/tree/master/VisualizationLearningCurves</url>
<abstract>
A learning curve visualizes changes in student performance over time. The line graph displays opportunities across the x-axis, and a measure of student performance along the y-axis. A good learning curve reveals improvement in student performance as opportunity count (i.e., practice with a given knowledge component) increases.
</abstract>
<description></description>

<inputs>
One or more <b>Student-Step</b> files.<br/>
An optional <b>Parameters</b> file for use in categorizing the curves. Without this file, the component will attempt to compute the model's slope so results will take longer to generate.
</inputs>

<outputs>
One or more image (.png) files, depicting the requested learning curve(s).
</outputs>

<options>
<b>Model: </b>the Knowledge Component (KC) model to plot<br/>
<b>View secondary: </b>flag indicating whether or not to display secondary model curves<br/>
<b>Secondary model(s): </b>one or more secondary KCs to include on graph<br/>
<b>Learning curve type: </b>Knowledge Components, Students, or All Students, All KCs (a composite across all students and all KCs) <em>The 'All KCs' option is deprecated.</em><br/>
<b>Learning curve metric: </b>Error Rate, Assistance Score, Number of Incorrects, Number of Hints, Step Duration, Correct Step Duration, or Error Step Duration<br/>
<b>Categorize curves: </b>flag indicating whether or not to categorize the generated learning curves<br/>
<b>Student threshold: </b>The categorization algorithm first discards points in each curve based on the <strong>student threshold</strong>. If a point has fewer than that number of students, it is ignored. (default: 10)<br/>
<b>Opportunity threshold: </b>Then, if the number of points is below the <strong>opportunity threshold</strong>, then that curve has <strong>too little data</strong>. (default: 3)<br/>
<b>Low Error threshold: </b>Next, if all points on the curve are beneath the <strong>low error threshold</strong>, then the curve is <strong>low and flat</strong>. (default: 20.0)<br/>
<b>AFM Slope threshold: </b>Then, if the slope of the predicted learning curve (as determined by the AFM algorithm) is below the <strong>AFM slope threshold</strong>, then the curve shows <strong>no learning</strong>. (default: 0.001)<br/>
<b>High Error threshold: </b>Finally, if the last point of the curve is above the <strong>high error threshold</strong>, then the curve is <strong>still high</strong>. (default: 40.0)<br/>
<b>Standard deviation cut-off: </b>The number of standard deviations above and below the mean for which to include data points.<br/>
<b>Max opportunities: </b>A maximum number of opportunities a student must have had with a KC for the student-KC pair to be included in the data.<br/>
<b>Error bar type: </b>No Error Bars, Standard Deviation, or Standard Error<br/>
<b>High-stakes CF name: </b>this is the name of a custom field that indicates if a step is high-stakes.
</options>

</info>
